



NGUYEN TRAN BINH NHU

FULL STACK DEVELOPER





Nhu is a Full Stack Developer who also has high levels of knowledge in other fields. She was previously an environmental engineer, where she was able to train her organizational skills as well as her attention to detail. Furthermore, she has experience as a web developer and gained essential skills both in programming and collaboration with other developers in a team. Overall, Nhu is a proactive individual who never wants to stop learning. The combination of her soft skills and hard skills make her an important asset for all Software Development companies.

SKILLS

FRONT-END DEVELOPMENT

Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, JavaScript React.js, Redux, SASS, Typescript.

BACK-END DEVELOPMENT

Flask, Python.

DATABASE MANAGEMENT

SQL.

OTHER

C, Canva, Visual Studio Code, Atom, Figma, Git, Miro.

LANGUAGES

English - Advanced

Finnish - Intermediate

Vietnamese - Native

Chinese - Novice

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Problem Solving Using Computational Thinking, University of Michigan on Coursera (May 2021)

RECENT PROJECTS

Yield System Website

Bootstrap, CSS, Figma, Ghost.js, HTML, REST API.

Developed the front-end module of a web application for Yield Systems where users can find the most updated information related to the company's activities, including but not limited to: partners and side projects.

flaskFarm

Bootstrap, Chart.js, CSS, Flask, HTML, JavaScript, Python, REST API, SQL.

flaskFarm is a Flask based web application for farm management, for instance, loading & visualization of data. Potential users could be a farm manager or a farmer.

React Weather App

CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React.js, React-Bootstrap.

This is a daily weather forecast data app created using Create-React-App and AccuWeather to get the weather data for a city and display it in a meaningful way.

EXPERIENCE

FULL-STACK DEVELOPER TRAINEE

Integrify | Helsinki, Finland | April-2022 - Present

- · Sharpening competence as a Full Stack Developer by collaborating with other developers of different seniorities on a diverse range of projects and real-life challenges.
- Focusing on front-end development with JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux in addition to other technologies and concepts such as accessibility and animations.
- Building back-end for web-based applications with frameworks such as Node.js and Express.js.
- · Covering additional concepts such as API development and documentation, unit testing with Jest, SQL and NoSQL databases, and version control with GitHub.
- · Working with DevOps practices (Bash scripting, Docker containers, and CI/CD with GitHub Actions) and Cloud Services with AWS.

JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER

Yield System Oy | Espoo, Finland | October 2021 - November 2021

- $\boldsymbol{\cdot}$ Developed website components using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, and REST API.
- · Facilitated collaboration with other developers to launch the web application.

ENVIRONMENTAL ENGINEER

Helsinki Region Environmental Services (HSY) | Espoo, Finland | September 2018 - October 2018

- · Participated in the mixed waste quality studies, which provided information on the composition of different types of waste from the Helsinki Metropolitan area.
- \cdot Responsible for sampling, sorting, and determining fractions of mixed waste, and used this information towards improvements in waste management.

WATER SYSTEMS ENGINEER

MARS Coporation (local name: SaoHoa) | Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam | September 2015 - November 2015

- · Estimated water supply demand in the system.
- · Designed treatment processes for handling domestic waste water.
- Designed pump systems and pipelines for both waste and supply water.

EDUCATION

M.SC. IN SUSTAINABLE MANAGEMENT OF INLAND AQUATIC RESOURCES

University of Jyväskylä | Jyväskylä, Finland | September 2016 - Present

B.ENG. IN ENVIRONMENTAL TECHNOLOGY AND MANAGEMENT

Van Lang University | Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam | September 2011 - June 2015